<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on the daily meh</title><link>https://nagimov.me/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on the daily meh</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 00:42:28 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nagimov.me/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Running docker on 32-bit hosts</title><link>https://nagimov.me/post/running-docker-on-32-bit-hosts/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 00:42:28 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nagimov.me/post/running-docker-on-32-bit-hosts/</guid><description>Docker is known to not to support 32-bit hosts. As per their debian installation instruction: Docker CE is supported on x86_64 (or amd64), armhf, and arm64 architectures. And that is plain wrong.
A tiny bit of extra support from docker-the-company would extend its use to older hardware, but (apparently) this is not a priority. &amp;ldquo;Let&amp;rsquo;s bring docker on 32-bit&amp;rdquo; issue was closed and locked in 2014, and nothing has changed since then.</description></item><item><title>alsa-utils&#39; arecord bug: lots of *.wav files, ignoring --duration parameter</title><link>https://nagimov.me/post/alsa-utils-arecord-bug-lots-of-wav-files-ignoring-duration-parameter/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 20:56:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nagimov.me/post/alsa-utils-arecord-bug-lots-of-wav-files-ignoring-duration-parameter/</guid><description>While working on a small side project at work, I found that I can&amp;rsquo;t record sound using Raspberry Pi with external USB sound card after upgrading it to Raspbian Jessie. Symptoms look rather weird: arecord doesn&amp;rsquo;t stop recording after a period of time specified by --duration flag, but keeps running and writing garbage to files like *-01.wav, *-02.wav and so on. Google doesn&amp;rsquo;t really give any solution to this (except the recommendation of terminating arecord using killall -KILL arecord after certain period of time).</description></item><item><title>Calibration of MAX31855 thermocouple converter</title><link>https://nagimov.me/post/max31855-thermocouple-to-digital-converter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 17:55:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nagimov.me/post/max31855-thermocouple-to-digital-converter/</guid><description>I have recently spent some time playing with Maxim 31855 chips, in a need of precise and cheap K-type thermocouple logger. It is a cheap voltage amplifier with digital SPI interface, so it works perfectly well with Raspberry Pi or Arduino.
There are many thermocouple amplifiers out there, and I am sure that most of them are properly calibrated for the temperature range around +/-50C, since even linear volt-to-degreeC conversion works fine in that range.</description></item><item><title>Amazon Fire TV 2nd Gen - Root &amp; OpenVPN</title><link>https://nagimov.me/post/fire-tv-2nd-gen-root-openvpn/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 19:35:32 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nagimov.me/post/fire-tv-2nd-gen-root-openvpn/</guid><description>My notes after spending half a day playing with my Fire TV.
While Amazon Fire TV seems to be the best htpc solution to me, it still requires rooting and a bit of patching on its way to a decent media center. I&amp;rsquo;m also used to US streaming services (Pandora, Netflix, Hulu, etc) which are only available through VPN, if you are outside of US. Rooting and setting up Kodi + OpenVPN is a way to go.</description></item></channel></rss>